<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CoralGablesMap</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main_menu">MainMenu</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_building_viewer">BuildingViewer</string>
    <string name="additional">Additional Images</string>
    <string name="go_inside">Go Inside</string>
    <string name="go_outside">Go Outside</string>
    <string name="title_activity_additional_images">AdditionalImages</string>
    <string name="congregational_church">Coral Gables Congregational Church</string>
    <string name="building01text01">The Congregational Church of Coral Gables was built in 1923 on a plot of land donated by George E. Merrick, the founder of Coral Gables. The church was completed on April 5th, 1925, making it the first church and public building in Coral Gables. Merrick dedicated the building to his father Solomon Merrick who was a Congregational minister. An architectural firm from Chicago, Kiehnel and Elliot, designed the building, modeling it on historical buildings from the colonial Americas and Europe. The Congregational Church, then, was one of the earliest buildings in Coral Gables to employ this Mediterranean style that became the hallmark of the first structures in the city, and is still an important component of the urban landscape to the present day. The Mediterranean style employed in the church is a composite created by Merrick and his architects which combined elements of historical architecture they had seen in books, drawings, and photographs with structures that they observed in their travels to Europe, Cuba, and other parts of Florida. The most important visual influences, however, came from Spanish Colonial architecture, a style that itself was composed of numerous eclectic elements. The building was meant to evoke the colonial history of the Americas, but also represent the beauty and majesty of venerable structures in Spain.</string>
    <string name="building01text02">The main facade of the church displays characteristics of the Spanish Colonial style in its highly ornamented doorway surrounding a traditional wooden door. Against the neutral stucco walls of the church, the white doorway stands out with its intricate and exuberant carvings. The style of the doorway connects it to artwork from the Baroque period, known for its drama, detail, and surface texture. The elaborate doorway acts like a theater backdrop, grabbing your attention and encouraging you to enter the church.</string>
    <string name="building01text03">The bell tower of a church was the tallest part of the structure and the best way to advertise the presence of a Christian building and associated religious community. The Congregational Church bell tower consists of a square profile with small balconies in the upper level, surmounted by similar decoration in white stucco to that of the church\'s main entrance. The tower opens up at the top to reveal a blue interior dome, perhaps a symbol of the celestial dome of the heavens. Though it contains no bells, the form of the tower evokes similar structures on historic Spanish churches, particularly the bell tower known as La Giralda at the Cathedral of Seville.</string>
    <string name="building01text04">The interior of the Congregational Church references another European historical style, that of the Romanesque, dating to the Middle Ages. The Romanesque is characterized by round arches that support thick walls leading up to a pointed roof and a wooden ceiling. The carved capitals atop the columns that separate the side aisles from the central nave are typical of a Romanesque church, as are the stained glass windows. Hanging from the ceiling are circular wrought iron chandeliers purchased in Spain that were donated by George Merrick. The interior culminates in the semi-circular apse, decorated in a grid pattern that captures one\'s attention upon entering the church through the main doorway.</string>
    <string name="building01text05">Carved wooden ceilings were central decorative elements in Spanish Colonial architecture, and the ceiling of the Congregational Church follows this colonial tradition. These ceilings were a hallmark of the Spanish Mudéjar style, one that combined patterns and forms from Islamic art in Spain and integrated them into a Christian artistic repertoire. The Mudéjar style was extraordinarily popular in Spain, as it manifested the uniqueness of Spanish culture, and the Spaniards proudly transported it with them to the colonies. It is in Latin America and the Caribbean that you can see some of the most creative adaptations of this Spanish style, particularly in the decoration of wooden ceilings in both religious and residential spaces.</string>
    <string name="building01text06">Wooden ceilings in the Spanish Colonial style were often decorated with intricate carvings, geometric patterning, inlay, and colorful paintings. This ceiling and other wooden elements in this church, however, are relatively unadorned. But if you look closely at the crossbeams that hold the superstructure together, or at other wooden supports in the church, you can see the painted decoration. Geometric and floral patterns in red, blue, and yellow contrast with the warm brown of the wood, and allude to the traditions of Spanish architecture from the Middle Ages to the modern period that George Merrick wished to evoke in the Mediterranean style architecture of Coral Gables. </string>
    <string name="building01">Coral Gables Congregational Church</string>
    <string name="building01exterior01">Detail of bell tower</string>
    <string name="building01exterior02">Informational plaque</string>
    <string name="building01exterior03">General view from the southwest</string>
    <string name="building01exterior04">Detail of façade with decorated portal</string>
    <string name="building01exterior05">General view from the southeast</string>
    <string name="building01exterior06">View of blue interior cupola in bell tower</string>
    <string name="building01exterior07">Windows on the eastern side aisle</string>
    <string name="building01exterior08">Northern exterior of church with bell tower</string>
    <string name="building01exterior09">Detail of arcade on north exterior wall</string>
    <string name="building01interior01">View to choir area and main entrance</string>
    <string name="building01interior02">Detail of Mudéjar style woodwork</string>
    <string name="building01interior03">View of apse and altar from choir balcony</string>
    <string name="building01interior04">Detail of apse decoration</string>
    <string name="building01interior05">Stained glass window on side aisles</string>
</resources>
